this problem
asks us to convert the case statement
that we wrote for part one
to an if statement
i'm going to comment out our case
statement
move it down a little
and write my if statement based off of
the existing code
we can see that if our local variable
stoplight references the string green
[Music]
we want to output go
if the value referenced by stoplight
is equal to the string yellow we'll
output slow down
and otherwise if stoplight is not equal
to green or yellow
we know it's equal to red and we want to
output the string
stop this code is very similar to the
case statement that we wrote previously
however you can see that even for this
very small problem
when using an if statement we've had to
explicitly compare stoplight
multiple times just to demonstrate that
this code works just the same with an if
statement
as it does in a case statement we'll run
the code
you